<Namespace Name="System.Configuration.Install">
  <Docs>
    <summary>Provides classes that allow you to write custom installers for your own components. The <see cref="T:System.Configuration.Install.Installer" /> class is the base class for all custom installers in .NET Framework.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[

## Remarks
 Through the <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Installers> property, an installer contains a collection of other installers as children. As the installer is executed, it cycles through its children and calls <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Install*>, <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Commit*>, <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Rollback*>, or <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Uninstall*>. For an example of an object in the <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Installers*> collection, see <xref:System.Diagnostics.EventLogInstaller>.

 The <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Context> property contains information about the installation. For example, information about the location of the log file for the installation, the location of the file that saves information required by the <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Uninstall*> method, and the command line that was entered when the installation executable was run. For an example of an installation executable, see [Installutil.exe (Installer Tool)](/dotnet/framework/tools/installutil-exe-installer-tool).

 The <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Install*>, <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Commit*>, <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Rollback*>, and <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Uninstall*> methods are not always called on the same instance of <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer>. For example, you might use an <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer> to install and commit an application, and then release the reference to that <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer>. Later, uninstalling the application creates a new reference to an <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer>, which means that the <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Uninstall*> method is called on a different instance of <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer>. For this reason, do not save the state of a computer in an installer. Instead, use an <xref:System.Collections.IDictionary> that is preserved across calls and passed into the <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Install*>, <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Commit*>, <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Rollback*>, and <xref:System.Configuration.Install.Installer.Uninstall*> methods.

 ]]></format>
    </remarks>
  </Docs>
</Namespace>
